COLIN MILLER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Contacts

520-250-0048

colinraymiller@gmail.com

https://github.com/colinrmiller

linkedin.com/in/colin-miller-587704212/

Projects

ScreenDraft - NSS Personal Project

- Social film discovery app, with designed to distinguish and highlight films based on user generated categories.
- · Generates user specific film preference data and algorithmically determines a dynamic total film ranking based on user decisions.
- · React, Material UI, Google OAuth
- View Code

Tabloi - NSS Team Project

- · Designed and built a full-stack video sharing web application.
- · Backend API built with ASP.NET
- · User Authentication with Firebase
- View Code

Nutshell - NSS Team Project

- · Designed and built a total task management, event reminder and messaging hub for use with mid-size social networks.
- · Designed a Facebook Messenger inspired messaging experience for realtime chat.
- View Code

SUMMARY

Transitioning into Professional Software Development has been a natural fit since moving away from a career in Math Education. Careful communicator and practiced problem solver with a background in Education and Engineering, excited to contribute to full-scale industrial applications.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER EXPERIENCE

APPRENTICE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School · 2021

NSS is a six-month intensive, full-time software development bootcamp focusing on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and server-side fundamentals with C++ and .NET.

- Single-page application development with React and with a focus on a modern ES6+ JavaScript design principles.
- Utilized .NET Core to build full-stack applications with a backend API.
- Database planning by building entity relationship diagrams (ERD) to define relationships with an emphasis on maintaining a flat data structure
- Utilized vanilla JavaScript (ES6), and React.js to create single page dynamic web applications using full CRUD functionality
- Styled applications using CSS, Bootstrap, reactstrap, and Material UI
- Built E2E testing suites, utilizing both BDD and TDD development methodologies.
- Completed 6 group project sprints while fully remote, comfortable with Slack, Zoom, GitHub Project, and wireframes for group communication and collaboration

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LEAD MATH INSTRUCTOR

Solutions4Education | Aug 2017 - August 2021

- Led math curriculum development for a private education company catering specifically to providing a certified high school diploma program for teenage boys enrolled in a private long-term drug rehabilitation program.
- Provided personalized instruction in the full high-school math and science curriculum, while catering to individual students capabilities and learning differences.
- Encouraged and mentored students in extracurricular educational goals including art, music, game design, programming, and machine learning.

FOOD SERVICE

Gallery of Food | September 2014 - August 2021

• Server & Catering Supervisor

49er Country Club | August 2012 - August 2014

• Server & Catering Supervisor

ADDITIONAL TECHNICAL PROJECTS

SUDOKU SOLVER

• Python implementation of Donald Knuth's algorithm for quickly finding depth first solutions for sudoku logic puzzles.

MISC. MATH VISUALIZERS

· Built assorted math visualization tools for classroom use using python and processing.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
 Git/Github
- React
- SQL Server
- CSS
- HTML
- C# .NET
- Python
- Cpp

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

Nashville Software School

B.S. AEROSPACE ENGINEERING

Minor: Mathematics University Of Arizona